ELIZABETH DIELENTHEIS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

As I neared the end of college, I felt the need to pivot my career trajectory towards something that allowed more opportunity to be creative, to tinker, and to problem-solve. Programming allows all of this and more; I love that so many languages and frameworks can be combined in different ways to create amazing things. I am a self-starter and fast learner, and after 17 weeks of learning full stack JavaScript, I have experience building the frontend and backend of web applications. I'm very excited to go beyond the classroom and continue learning while creating something impactful!

CONTACT

■ elizabeth.dielentheis@gmail.com

651-769-5153

♀ San Francisco. CA

in /in/edielentheis

Dielentheis

SKILLS

Proficient: JavaScript, Express, Node.js, AngularJS, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, HTML5, Git, jQuery, Test-Driven Development

Some Experience: C++, SQL, SCSS/CSS3, Gulp, web scraping, Socket.io, Tessel, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Twitter Bootstrap, Material Design

Learning: React, Redux

EDUCATION

Grace Hopper at Fullstack Academy

Immersive 17-week software engineering bootcamp in NYC

Tufts University

B.S. Cognitive and Brain Sciences 2016 Relevant Courses: Intro to Computer Science, Data Structures, Human-Computer Interaction GPA: 3.6, cum laude

Danish Institute for Study AbroadClinical Psychology 2015

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Nationally Registered EMT

Registration #E3231759

Proficient in French

PROJECTS

"Plont" | Full Stack Engineer | github | deployed

- Web app designed to assist home gardeners in creating, maintaining, and optimizing the layout of a garden plot
- Takes local weather, space, sun, and specific plants' needs into consideration
- Sends notifications to user if weather in their area will be too dry for plants and when it's time to plant or harvest
- Responsible for algorithm design/implementation, schema design, backend routes/API, state controllers, and rendering plot on frontend
- Uses JavaScript, Express, Node.js, Angular, Sequelize, Material Design

"Don't Tell Me" | Sole Engineer | github

- Chrome extension that blocks Game of Thrones spoilers from user's Facebook newsfeed
- Available in the Chrome Web Store
- Uses chrome.* APIs, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

"Well This is Awkward" | Engineer

- Hardware hackathon project that monitors conversation between two people, detects awkward silences, and then texts a conversation starter to the user. Also plays cricket noises and waves small flag.
- Responsible for text message sending through TextBelt API
- Uses Tessel 2, JavaScript

EMPLOYMENT

Tufts Center for Reading and Language Research Research Assistant

Medford, MA Oct 2015 to May 2016

- Collaborated with MIT to create in-classroom robot to improve children's language skills
- Identified and classified key indicators of child's speech maturity level and linguistic capability using the Index of Productive Syntax

DevTech Research Group

Programming Fundamentals Teaching Assistant

Medford, MA Sep 2014 to Dec 2014

 Taught low socioeconomic status second graders fundamentals of computer programming using iPads and ScratchJr, an app which allows children to explore concepts like modularity, repetition, and sequencing through game creation and storytelling

Tufts Jumpstart

Jumpstart Corps Member

Medford, MA Sep 2012 to Aug 2013

• Completed 2 AmeriCorps terms of service through teaching curriculum oriented towards language development in low-income preschools